Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): So it's amazing to me that over 20 years after the Iraq War, its architects and supporters are still not fully in control of America's foreign policy, but certainly influential in it. And it's shocking to me that two months
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): after Trump's landslide
victory, a race
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): in which he ran against the neocons, the neocons are still brazen enough to try and influence...
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): and sabotage his nominations. We
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): are days, but less than a week before Tulsi Gabbard's hearings. Where are we
In
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): the below-the-radar
Man 4: war between permanent Washington's national security establishment, the neocons, and the incoming Trump administration. I
think
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): it's unclear. So, as of this recording, 10 minutes ago, Mr. Hegseth,
Man 6: the defense secretary, was just confirmed on a 50-50 vote. Hegseth is an interesting character, I believe a former colleague of yours. Yes. He appears to have done a bit of a conversion.
Man 6: uh on his foreign policy uh uh beliefs and the best evidence of that is the
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): people that he's picked so
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): far so his cadres the people that will serve okay i ask you to pause right there so what you're this is relevant to people who know pete hegseth
from
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): clips on x of him from
Man 11: eight years ago saying things that would lead you to believe he's
a
Speaker 12: pretty stout
Man 11: neocon yeah
but
Okay, so
Man 11: that's what you're referring to.
Speaker 13: Yeah, I mean,
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): I think the available evidence is that he is, like, circa 10 years ago was a pretty
Man 15: conventional Republican. Yes. And he has changed his life in more ways than one. Yes. And so
he is
Man 15: a question mark. But the early
Man 6: evidence is the people that he has chosen to surround himself are stark departures from the man from 10 years ago.
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): And so, that's a big deal, and especially in a place like the Pentagon, which is hard to control.
Man 17: Yes, and wants no change under any circumstances, except an annual increase in the number of four-star generals. It's the largest bureaucracy on Earth. It is. And it exists to serve itself. It's got a pretty abysmal record of winning wars, a pretty great record of spending money. It desperately needs reform. And you're saying that based on the personnel choices you think he's making, he's now the defense secretary, by the way,
as of right now.
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): that he is like sincerely on board with Trump's foreign policy. Yeah,
Speaker 18: I mean, he did not need to make these picks. I mean, I don't think he needed to make these picks to get confirmed. I don't think
Man 15: he needed these picks to win any senators. He is courting, I think, minor controversy
Man 6: now, which is why we're having this meeting. He did not need to do this. It was a move of conviction and belief and principle in
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): his early days in office.
So
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): give us an example. Just give us an example of what you're talking about. Sure. There's going to be this Michael D'Amino figure who will have the Middle
Man 6: East portfolio. He has been advised throughout the process by another figure named Daniel Caldwell. These are both, you know, people in their 40s or 30s, you know, basically millennials who are veterans of the global war on terror. They're very much in the— So they fought in that. Yeah, Dan did.
Man 15: Yeah. And Michael was a CIA agent.
Man 15: So yeah, these are the
Man 6: guys that were hunting down IRGC, Iranian Revolutionary Guard, core people, and the forever wars that Trump and Vance ran on reforming and ending, et cetera, et cetera. And so they're very much in the Vance mold of, we went there, not really sure what the point was, and we want to roll back from that
Man 15: somewhat. I think you might have heard this message from Mr. Trump
At
Man 15: least once or twice in the last 10 years.
So
Speaker 19: these, I don't know, Damien, I know Caldwell, who I think of as a man of
Speaker 20 (lower-pitched voice): genuine integrity, high intelligence, and principle committed to his country. I think he's proven that. Yeah. I honestly
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): think he's like a wonderful person. But he's being attacked by people who never served with a
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): long, unbroken track record of destroying America. Yeah.
As
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): somehow anti-American?
Man 15: Yeah. How does this work? Yeah, I mean, I think that the tactics are pretty clear. So, no one reads
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): anything. Everybody is cynical, confused. Says the magazine editor, nobody reads anything. You're right. Get a headline out there. Call someone a naughty word. Say they're anti-American.
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): uh a country uh or they are uh um radical um you know if the anyone sues this publication it will take years and years and years and hope that some club member uh at mar-a-lago hands this to president trump exactly and tries to trick him and thinks that mr trump is a stupid man and this is the approach
And
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): this is what
Man 15: they are trying to do. - That's exactly. - And it is a cyclone. I mean, the word has been abused by the Democrats. - They've done this to me, yes. - But it is, this is actual disinformation. - Yes. - I hate to use the word, but like, because- - What are
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): the publications, who are the people involved in this campaign of lies?
Man 23: - Okay, I mean, I'm not familiar
and I
Man 23: don't know any of the people over there personally,
but
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): the big story that's going around,
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): on both Domino and I believe Caldwell is from Jewish Insider. And again, no one really wants to be, you know, attacked by something called Jewish Insider. It doesn't sound very fun. And so they are running headlines
Man 23: against people and they are attacking them. And what they do is they don't say anything that is,
per se
Man 23: inaccurate, but they totally strip the context for everything. So
Speaker 24: what, let's go one by one. Gino Domino? Just by correspondence. Okay. And what's
Speaker 25: yours? Is this a radical figure, anti-American figure? No,
Man 23: this is somebody who wants to pull back, I would say, moderately from the Middle East, which I
Man 26: think at this point is...
Man 26: basically bipartisan outside of the radicals within Washington, D.C. and the Beltway.
Speaker 27 (lower-pitched voice): - Okay, I think this is a fair assessment. So the people who want to continue what we're
Man 4: doing at unsustainable cost, being a bankrupt country, by the way, sending aid to countries that are not bankrupt. Those are the radicals, I think it's fair to say. So what are they saying about
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): D'Amino in this hit piece? - They are trying to make the reader jump to the
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): conclusion that he is anti-Israeli,
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): that he is pro-Iranian. He's pro-Iranian? Pro-Iranian. Okay. He is somehow pro-radical Islam. You know, he's pro all the scary people
in the
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): Middle East. Radical Islam.
Speaker 28: Sure. Whatever. It doesn't really matter. I
Speaker 29: don't know the guy.
It
Speaker 30: sounds kind of Catholic to me. They think, they think. You know a lot of Shiites called Domino,
or is
Speaker 30: that
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): a common name for Persians?
Not to my
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): information. Okay. And again, I think it bears repeating
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): that this person, like, was responsible for the tracking of Revolutionary Guard Corps members in Iran, potentially sent some of them to their death. So the whole thing has an opera buffet flavor to it that he's being attacked as— So
what
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): you're saying is these are people who will say anything. It doesn't matter. They're kind of from the very white
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): school of journalism, just like you have an objective, something you want to achieve—
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): And whatever it takes to get there is fine. You will say it. It doesn't matter. You'll call anybody anything if it serves your purpose.
Speaker 32: They are
Man 31: very, very willing to destroy
Speaker 32: this person with absolutely no
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): compunction.
Is there any evidence
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): that he's, quote, anti-Israel? None. Right. None. And in fact, there's evidence of
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): the contrary, which he praises the country. Yeah. So, okay. He is critical
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): of aspects of the war.
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): It's okay to be critical of other people's wars or your own wars. It's
Speaker 27 (lower-pitched voice): okay to offer analysis of war. Or
to
Man 23: even state that it's not, in fact, our war, as the president of the United States just did on his inauguration day, emphasizing from
Man 31: behind the Resolute Desk that it's their war, not our war. So
Speaker 34 (lower-pitched voice): I read something from a guy called David Wormser, who was one of the architects of the Iraq
Man 4: war, not from this country, not really concerned with this country—
Man 4: at all, and also I
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): think it's fair to say, you know, someone who should hang his head in shame, given a lifetime of destruction that he's helped bring
to
Man 17: our country, but describe these policies as anti-American. So I have
to say, it
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): takes a lot of balls for someone who has no interest in the United States to accuse someone whose whole orientation is helping the United States of being anti-American, but I've noticed this a lot. If you...
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): raised the question like, what are we getting out of this? You know, the endless war cycle, we're getting bankruptcy, obviously, but like, is this good for us? They'll accuse you, you know, the Constantine Kizzen, also not an American, will accuse, that wing will accuse you of being somehow woke and you're like left wing
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): for asking these questions. Have you noticed this? Yeah, I mean, it's interesting that you raise some of these figures. We go into this all night. I'd like to. Yeah, they're hoping. There's no more repulsive
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): group in American life.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): than the people who continue to push death and bankruptcy on the United States. I think that's fair. Can't recover from death.
No,
Speaker 35: you can't.
So, I mean, I
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): think that they're hoping that Americans don't do the reading.
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): They're hoping that Americans read X posts. They're hoping that Americans watch random
Man 6: cable news hosts, that they're zoned out and they have, you know, let's say they have a positive view of, you know, certain aspects of America's role in the Middle East and they start tar and feathering people on
Man 15: the internet and that there's no pushback on it. At the same time...
But
Speaker 36: it's just, I guess the only
reason...
I
Man 17: have noticed this is because it's so over the top rather than look,
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): I think a lot of these positions are legitimate. I disagree with them. You know, a ton of these people are smart people. I know almost all of them. And they could make like a straightforward case for their position. Like, here's why we should affect regime change in Iran or here's why we should kill Putin. I mean, maybe there's a case to be made for that, but they never make the case. They attack anyone who stands in their way.
in
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): the most brutal and dishonest ways, they have no limits at all in their behavior at all.
And I just
Speaker 37: find that repugnant and like corrosive. Even if I agreed with them, I'd be against that. Like, what is that?
It's
Speaker 38: guerrilla warfare, the win at any costs.
Man 4: Win at
Speaker 37: any costs. I
know I'm jumping
Man 4: around, but I'm exercised. I just watched what's happening to a man called Steve Whitcoff. Do you know Steve Whitcoff?
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): Yes. Do
you know who
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): that is? Okay. So he's a friend of Trump's. He's a real estate guy from New York. I happen to know him just for other reasons. How well do you know him?
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): Pretty well, you know, just personally, I don't know a ton about his views. I
don't sense
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): that we probably don't agree on foreign policy in some ways, but he was tasked by Trump, as you know, to go over and affect some kind of ceasefire between Israel and Hamas, and he did.
And I
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): doubt he's anti-Israel. In fact, I know he's not, whatever that means. And he is being attacked.
is
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): somehow an agent of the Islamic Republic of Qatar and like anti-Israel Steve Wyckoff. Yeah.
And I happen to really
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): like Steve Wyckoff. I think he's just, I just like him. He's just a great guy, actually. And he's really tough and he's just a good guy. If you had dinner with him, you'd
Speaker 39 (lower-pitched voice): like him, trust me. But I'm just blown away by the dishonesty. Rather than say, hey, Steve Wyckoff, like I disagree with you or whatever. It's he's working for Qatar.
Speaker 39 (lower-pitched voice): no what he's from like
Speaker 40: long island what are you talking about this
is
Man 15: the higher profile i mean like i mean they're hoping again that uh that trump has learned nothing they insult the president's
Speaker 41: but these people are disgusting
Speaker 37: as well they're liars and like if there's one thing the country said too much of it's lying let's just stop lying let's just be honest i agree yes i agree we've been corroded by lies completely the country's about to collapse because
Speaker 39 (lower-pitched voice): of lies and
The
Speaker 39 (lower-pitched voice): people pushing endless war are one of
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): the main vectors for that lying, like because there's just no reference point in reality at all. If Steve Wyckoff is an agent of the Islamic Republic, then I just give up.
Do you know
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): what I mean? Yeah.
No. Okay,
Speaker 42: sorry, lecture over.
Man 23: No, no, no, no, I mean, the Wyckoff thing in some ways is what set the whole thing up, right? Wyckoff? He's like the most
Speaker 43: reasonable,
Speaker 44: moderate person in the world. No, he's not anti-Israel. He's just tough. I think
the
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): Wyckoff thing surprised both sides, though, I would note. So I think, so obviously you knew him before, within recent
Man 6: years. Okay, so I think in general, the open source intelligence to use a,
Man 15: lame term but like i would say is that the hawks um people who want to say go all the way on iran uh
did
Man 6: not expect wikof to be uh so pragmatic and then additionally the realist and restraint camp also did not expect it did not all the all the reporting from say israeli media say haretz or
Man 6: That Wyckoff went in there and sort of with both the incoming Trump administration and, you know, the remnants of the of the Biden administration forced Prime Minister Netanyahu into some sort of deal, a deal that he had turned down six months ago in May of 2024, basically identical deal
Man 15: that through most everybody in the loop for a loop. And
Man 23: that has
Man 6: set off, as far as I can infer,
a.
Man 6: climate of hysteria within israel itself at least among the i'm not sure sir netanyahu himself but at least
Man 23: within the factions of his cabinet that are hard line as hell okay so they
Speaker 45: disagree you know they've had to give a little everyone does not a
Man 23: disagreement i mean like this will not stop unless there's pushback
All
Speaker 46: I'm saying is when you reach an agreement, everyone gets pinched. Okay. That's
just
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): the nature of it. Right.
And no
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): one likes it, you know, but like tough, that's what it is. And my read on Wyckoff is that he's just not super ideological. I think he's pro-Israeli. You know, I wouldn't
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): even question that, but I don't think he's an ideologue. He's a, he's a self-made real estate guy who started with like a single apartment building in Washington Heights.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): Sure. He's a tough human.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): - Yeah. - And I think you need someone who's practical and tough to affect a negotiation. You don't want someone who's captived all kinds of theories. Trump says, "Hey, Wyckoff, get a peace deal," or, you know, "Get a
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): ceasefire, an intermediate peace deal," a first step toward one. - Yeah. - And Wyckoff's like, "Okay." And he just shows up and he's like, "Hey, you, you." - Yeah. - You're like, that's, isn't that
Man 15: what you want? - I think a lot of Israel was
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): surprised by this.
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): I mean, I mean, I mean, this, this was lost in the absolute cacophony of 2020, 24. Really? But yes, like if you, if you read, I read the Israeli press daily
Man 6: and, you know, there were members of Netanyahu's coalition. So these are members of the prime minister Netanyahu, people who are not in his party, who are more hardline than him. And they were saying, Trump's really talking about this endless war stuff. This might be a problem. and this was back in October and September
and August.
Man 6: and no one was paying attention 'cause it was brat summer and other things were going on, but this was coming. And the fact that they got it done, not even before, not even during the transition itself, also surprised
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): people. And so-
Speaker 34 (lower-pitched voice): - I'm sensing inflated expectations here. I mean, this is a foreign country, obviously an ally, a close ally, the closest ally, I think it's fair
Speaker 47: to say,
Speaker 34 (lower-pitched voice): but a separate country. And
Man 4: so-
You
Man 4: know, I think realistic expectations would be we get some of what we want. We don't get everything we want because, you know, we're not in charge of the United States.
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): Okay, but there's a tension here. I mean, so first, the relationship between the
Man 6: president of the United States and the prime minister of Israel is extremely unclear. Yes. Yes. I don't think maybe only the two of them now. They have disagreed since at
Man 15: least—
Man 15: 2020 over the election but they probably disagreed beforehand
Man 6: over strikes um in iran the last time you and i spoke publicly um was over the soleimani strike in january of 2020 um and there were since then reporting in the last five years has come out that the two of them disagreed over that uh trump felt uh that the israelis didn't do their part etc etc etc so for years for at least half a decade the well has been poisoned between trump and netanyahu doesn't mean the relationship is done.
Man 6: But there's
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): been an atmosphere of mistrust and-- - Well,
Man 4: he's had that, you know, I've watched closely and, you know, interviewed him more than once. And, you know, for-- - Then you have him. - Yeah, for, you know, well, moving on 30 years. - Yeah.
Speaker 48: - 'Cause he's been in and out of office. And he's had complicated relations with every president. - Yeah. -
You know?
Speaker 49 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah, I mean, I think the key thing to understand for your listeners, anyone who's not turning
Man 6: this off because we're getting into the depths of Israeli politics here, but Netanyahu's situation is unstable. Yes. A super majority of Israelis want him out. They want him to resign. He does not want to resign because if he resigns, he may go to prison. And also, he's been a power achiever for 30 years. And I've noticed that...
Man 6: People who do that often don't like to quit. I think that's
Speaker 50: fair. Yeah,
Man 6: okay. So he doesn't want to quit for both reasons of his
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): freedom and, you know, the way of his life. Yeah. Yes, okay. Pretty
Speaker 51: recognizable syndrome, I would say. Yes, yes. Not confined to BB. It's international. Yes,
it
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): is international. Okay, so how does
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): he not quit? It's pretty clear that spectacular circumstances justify his presence. It's very similar, actually. I mean,
there's been
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): comparisons between him and churchill it's actually fair um only in wartime can someone like netanyahu at this point get a position i get it the war has to
go on
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): so what war
Man 23: so they have basically a deal with hezbollah i think it's not like i think that is by far the least likely that they're going to go back in there there are
Man 6: basically two options one once all the hostages are exchanged then they go back into gaza okay
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): or
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): I
Man 6: guess 1B, is to do the West
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): Bank, which is already going
on right now, or
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): two. - What do you mean do the West Bank?
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): - Invade it, annex it. - And what about the people who live there? Like what happens to them? - Not Israel's problem.
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): - What do you do while you're in the West Bank? I mean, what are you doing there? What is the point of the operation, do you know? - To annex the territory and build developments.
Man 6: I mean, this is, I mean, and you know, the unstated thing is that they'll either export these people or eliminate them.
And
Man 6: so it's
pretty
Man 23: terrifying stuff. It's not light stuff, but this is not a light interview. And so the problem is the U.S. is the military underwriter of this. The Israelis probably can't do this without us selling them weapons. And so while Americans are tuned out and not thinking
about this
Man 23: kind of thing, our reputation overseas is one of arms dealer. And over time, that affects your children,
it's
Man 23: being able to travel abroad that affects america's reputation overseas it's
dicey stuff
Speaker 53: well it caused 9 11 among other things right so yeah it has effects for sure
Man 26: yeah right option two yeah is iran yep which is which is as i'll just quote them i'll
Man 31: quote the the hardline perspective itself it's the head of the snake in the conception of the israeli hardline and also the neoconservative right in the united states for sure
and so
Man 31: Israel also can't do Iran, in my view, and also in general assessments, without the help of the United States. It's usually joint U.S.-Israeli airstrikes, or even
a solo
Man 31: invasion of Iran by the United States is
Man 26: the ultimate sort of fantasy. I'm
going to need
Speaker 54: more coffee to proceed because you're blowing my mind, Kurt Mills.
When
Speaker 55 (lower-pitched voice): we first did a deal with Black Rifle Coffee, Evan, the CEO, sent us like a case of coffee beans. And honestly, I have not had any
Man 11: coffee since then. In the past eight months, it's not made by Black Rifle. We are obsessed. And it's not just coffee. They've got high-performance energy drinks, tons of merch that's very
cool.
It
Man 11: is the best, and we can say that as daily obsessive users of the product. Black Rifle Coffee is awesome, and by the way, Black Rifle itself is awesome. The company is filled with special forces veterans working there, bringing you the best products on the market. Black Rifle has always been more than just
Man 17: about must-have offerings. They're committed to supporting veterans, first responders, law enforcement. Every purchase provides funding to those groups and gear.
Man 17: The people who are protecting us, who are the heart of this country. From premium coffee roast, ready to drink cans to American gear, every item designed to give you a sense of this country. Black Rifle Coffee, blackriflecoffee.com. Use the code Tucker for 30% off on your first order or simply grab one of their items off your grocery shelves in your town. We drink it. We recommend it.
Just
Man 17: one quick digression
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): about Steve Wyckoff. Sure. I think it's really significant that he's not a professional foreign policy figure. He hasn't spent a career at the State Department or, you
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): know, doing bilaterals for his career. You know,
he's
Speaker 39 (lower-pitched voice): just a smart, tough, competent person who was charged with a task by the president and he got it done. And maybe we need more of
Speaker 57: that.
I mean, I
Speaker 57: do, you know, there are certain parts of statecraft that, you know, probably it's helpful to have experience in
Speaker 43: statecraft, but, but some of it's just pretty straightforward. Yeah. They get a ceasefire. Okay. Yeah. No, no, I know.
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): I mean, I think there has. Could anyone from the state department have done what Steve Wyckoff did, do you think? No, especially without the, without the president's matter. Well, of course not. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 58: But even if Trump had like called someone in and been like, okay, Mr. Career Diplomat, can you affect a ceasefire? He'd be like, well, it's very
Speaker 59: complicated. Wiccaf's just a cat.
Speaker 59: Hey, ceasefire, stop. No,
it's the
Speaker 60 (lower-pitched voice): same. I mean, like, the international relations has been made into, they have to make it into, like, a
Man 61: pseudoscience. Exactly.
Speaker 62: Smart. Just
Speaker 37: like everything else. Yeah, just like everything else. Just like journalism or...
Speaker 37: Yeah. Even education. Like you can't teach third grade without a master's degree. Are you kidding? Yeah. So it's just needlessly complex.
When the
Speaker 37: first
Speaker 64: requirement is, do you like third graders? It's nothing to do with your master's degree. The whole thing isn't, it's absurd.
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah. And then, you know, it's the same thing with all of academia, which is like people's theses are increasingly more Baroque and like
Man 6: nobody actually knows large things like the Israeli Palestinian conflict, or at least know it in a way that is applicable in religion.
Man 6: Power in real life and I mean, maybe things are changing now But like also a lot of the foreign policy establishment It's different now in the second term, but
Man 15: wouldn't work with the first Trump term wouldn't work with their team
And I
Man 15: think that was through discredit of the country. I think I think that was I think that just did not serve the country
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): Well, of
Speaker 27 (lower-pitched voice): course it didn't serve the country Well, we know the country hasn't been served because look at the country and
So I
Speaker 27 (lower-pitched voice): think you know, we can say of all
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): players and
They
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): didn't serve the country, that would include the media, and there have been times when I didn't serve the country, like when I advocated for the Iraq War. I mean, we're all culpable to some extent, but
it's just
Man 4: remarkable to me that people are continuing it. So now, instead of telling us that Saddam has weapons of mass destruction or that Osama bin Laden attacked us for our freedoms or whatever the lie of the day was—
Man 4: Um, the new idea is that Iran is, quote, the head of the snake. How many Americans have been killed by Iranian
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): proxies in the United States over the last 20 years, do you think? How many Americans in the United States? Yeah, have been killed by Iran-sponsored terrorism. Zero. Right around zero. How many have died of fentanyl ODs, drugs whose precursors come from China?
Speaker 66: Millions.
Well, more than
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): a million. Uh...
more than a
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): million yeah okay i think i mean look like to play
Speaker 67: no i mean what are you talking about
Man 15: the iranians back proxies that killed u.s troops in the iraq war yeah of course but but we shouldn't have
Man 6: done the
iraq war well
Speaker 34 (lower-pitched voice): iran took over iraq because we took out saddam hussein in a majority shiite country i
Man 4: happen to be there for that and even i as a 33 year
Speaker 27 (lower-pitched voice): old moron was like wait a in just a basic interest in demographics? Like, isn't this going to go to Iran now?
Speaker 27 (lower-pitched voice): - Yep. - Anyway, yes. Right.
Speaker 46: But
I
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): just find it amazing that there's
been no
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): public conversation about whether or not the United States
should
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): go to war with Iran. There's been no case laid out. At
least in
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): 2002, they had the decency to lie to us in
a
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): pretty complicated, sophisticated way about weapons of mass destruction. Now it's just like, shut up. You're anti-American if you ask questions.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): And it feels like we're moving toward a conflict with Iran. Is that a fair?
I think we
Man 6: have been moving towards one. And, you know, I think basically the biggest risk of a democratic administration is a war with Russia. And the biggest risk of a republican administration is a war with Iran. So my rule is always that's why it's more ethical to be a republican because at least the Iranians don't have nukes yet.
So
Man 15: that's actually like pretty close to my first principle, like just outright.
we
Man 6: have
Man 6: But the Iran war would be still like the worst and like not something that we should pursue. And look, foreign policy experts at this point will chime in on this conversation being like, oh, well, that's just so unrealistic. That's not actually what we want. This is actually just ridiculous externality. But I think it is worth noting that.
Man 6: We have done
Man 15: wars, toppling governments throughout the region over the last 25 years. So number one, it's happened very recently. Number two, it is kind of the explicit goal of the hardliners. And the hardliners keep moving the overage window in their direction. And so while this is perhaps not 100% certain, but hardly, there is a hard drive towards doing this and picking off Pentagon deputies
Man 15: And allowing leaders like Trump and Vance to be surrounded by hawks and no dissenting voices whatsoever is absolutely essential
Speaker 69: towards any road to war.
And I
Speaker 39 (lower-pitched voice): have to say the amount of calculated deception on the right.
So
Man 4: all of a sudden Barry Weiss, who's a leftist, becomes a conservative because she's against trannyism or something.
You
Man 4: know,
Speaker 39 (lower-pitched voice): every normal person is against that. But it's pretty obvious
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): that the whole purpose of her organization, the Free Press, and her career in journalism is
to kind
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): of soften up the right for war with Iran
and to
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): attack
Speaker 39 (lower-pitched voice): anybody. And she had this whole constellation of people, you know, Neil Ferguson and all these kind of people who had weight to the project, but who really are all kind of paid...
To
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): flack for war with Iran and attack anyone who's not with the program. I felt the sting of this so I didn't really understand how this worked, but then You
know someone
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): with like thoroughly moderate foreign policy views. I don't really want war with anybody. I'm not against anybody And all of
a sudden
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): you're like wow, you know people are calling you
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): anti-american
Well, there's
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): precedent for this so what you're just I don't know I don't know any of the people you described personally But I'm just
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): saying like there was you said the problem with voting Republican is you're more likely to wind up with a
war
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): with Iran. And I agree with you, I'd much rather have a war with Iran than a war with Russia, but kind of don't want either one. And it's just interesting how the groundwork, I just know, because I've been in conservative media my whole
life, all of
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): a sudden all these
Speaker 57: new people and you're like, oh, Barry Weiss, are you really conservative? Well, not at all. Then what
are you
Speaker 57: doing here? Oh, you're trying to convince me that I'm not allowed to oppose a war with Iran or I'm going to be
Speaker 39 (lower-pitched voice): written out of the conservative movement or something.
Speaker 70: Okay, so a lot of people are comparing Trump to Reagan these days,
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): and I think it is...
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): an inaccurate comparison, but there obviously are
Man 6: comparisons that are very different human beings based on my position. So if you accept that Trump is the biggest cheese since Reagan on the Republican side, what happened in the
Man 15: Reagan years? So the neoconservatives, that is people who came from the left and moved to the right, were very, very savvy.
Man 15: effective and reasonable at domestic policy. They were very, very good on the crime issues of the day. And their periodicals gained currency because, hey, actually we should clean
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): up the streets of New York, et cetera, et cetera, et cetera, et cetera, et cetera. - I knew a lot
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): of them, and some of them were really smart, decent people too. And by the way, some of their foreign policy viewers were not crazy at all. They recognized the Soviet Union
Speaker 57: was evil. Like the first generation of
neocons
Speaker 57: Midge Dector. I mean, I kind of love Midge Dector. I don't know. You know what I mean? I don't think that they were all nuts at all.
Speaker 49 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah. But by the nineties and two thousands, you know, if you believed in, uh, you know, some crime
Man 6: enforcement in New York, you also had to believe towards the march towards regime change in Iraq. And so again, again, don't want
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): to sound like that
Speaker 30: part of the buffet line. Yeah.
I will
Speaker 30: take the safe city and the thriving economy. I'm going to leave out the Forever War.
Speaker 30: But I think it
Speaker 71: is the essential pitch of this new generation of
Man 15: neoconservatism, which of course does not call itself
Man 6: that, but it is moderation on the social issues. Let's turn down the volume. And at the same time, over here in the column space over here, a little
news item
Man 6: about what's going on in the Red Sea and why the U.S. needs to care.
and
Man 6: it's a drip, drip, drip, drip, drip, drip. And it can go on for months and years and years and
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): years. And all of a sudden we super care about the Houthis in Yemen. We super care about Iran. And we have to underwrite a war in Israel until every
Man 6: single member of Hamas is dead. And it's just not
Speaker 69: clear that the US national interest is there.
To put
Speaker 69: it lightly.
Speaker 39 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah. And I guess what I object to is, I mean, I'm never offended by people with different ideas. I'm never offended by
someone
Speaker 27 (lower-pitched voice): who makes a sincere case, affirmative case or something that I disagree with. Okay. And by the way, maybe he's right and I'm wrong. I've certainly been wrong a lot.
The part where I
Speaker 27 (lower-pitched voice): get
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): enraged is the bad faith. Yeah.
Yeah.
And
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): so you ask questions like, well, is this in our interest? Well, you hate
Speaker 37: so-and-so. I don't hate anybody. And I certainly don't hate that. Certainly don't hate that country. I like it a lot, actually.
But
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): there's no room for
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): it. They don't, they're preventing discussion. Yeah. And a lot of these people have the gall of,
to
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): describe themselves as warriors for free speech when, of course, free speech is the last thing they want. And they've gone out of their way to prevent any kind of open conversation about the most important topics in our collective life. So
I'm just
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): bothered
Speaker 74 (lower-pitched voice): by the lying.
Speaker 75: There's too much lying, don't you think? Absolutely. I
would
Speaker 76: say, and by the way, I'll even go farther and say, having worked for Bill Kristol for years,
- Five
Speaker 41: and a half
Man 61: years. - William Crystal, the editor of the Weekly Standard, that was the absolute launching point magazine of the Iraq War.
Speaker 77: - For sure,
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): and I was there. I mean, I started the very first day of the Weekly Standard, August 1st, 1995, 30 years ago. And I thought Bill Crystal, I still would say, was a great boss,
you know?
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): Interesting, fun to talk to, funny as hell. Obviously, I think he's taken a really dark turn and his life has been kind of a disaster and I feel bad for him.
But
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): one thing
Speaker 57: I'll say about Bill Kristol circa, you know, 2000 is that he would make an
Speaker 39 (lower-pitched voice): actual case for his views. He would say, we have to go in and take out Saddam for the following eight reasons. And he would write— And you would
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): say, this is in 95, 96, 97. I mean,
I
Speaker 78: was there for all of that. And I wasn't paying super close attention because
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): I was dumb. And
I was
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): focused on other things. And I was like, oh, yeah, it's a foreign policy hobby horse. You know, he's into that stuff. I'm not that into it. I didn't understand the stakes. I didn't really understand anything, actually. I mean, I was like
Speaker 39 (lower-pitched voice): a kid. But—
I
Speaker 39 (lower-pitched voice): always admired and still admire his willingness and that generation's willingness to make their case, to write some paper. Here's what we're for.
That is gone. And
Speaker 39 (lower-pitched voice): now it's just like, can we censor the people? Can we call them names to the point where they get kicked off social media so there's no counterargument?
Well, even
Speaker 39 (lower-pitched voice): Crystal
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): himself had stopped writing.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): well, he could never write, you know, not a genius, I will say, but, you know, an affable, amusing person in meetings, you know, I mean, I mean, probably the most successful
Speaker 79: political organizer of the last 30
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): years. Yeah. And, and tireless, you know, and there are good things to be said about Bill Kristol. Obviously I'm, he's called me a Nazi like a hundred times, but that's kind of
the point.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): I'm not a Nazi. I'm not for the Nazis. I just don't,
I've
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): got different views, and that's the turn that I'm really bothered by, is just the pure ad hominem attempts at censorship, and Barry Weiss engages in that, like,
Speaker 74 (lower-pitched voice): relentlessly behind the scenes, using all kinds of proxies, some of whom I know.
And I
Speaker 27 (lower-pitched voice): just want to say it out loud. I just want to say, oh, this is this is deception here. OK, so I hope people know that. I
Man 6: think it makes it impossible for the new president to do what he's promised to do if he doesn't solve this conundrum.
Tell
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): me what you mean. So, I mean, if the president wants to send troops to the U.S. border and the Trump
Man 15: and the president wants to rebuild the American economy and the president wants to focus on.
on
Man 15: china yes
Man 6: and the president wants the moral credibility to end the russia ukraine war at some point yes expanding the war in the middle east even with prolonged
Man 15: arms sales corrodes his political capital who's gonna pay for
that
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): the united states
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): No, but I mean, we literally are operating in the red to the tune of trillions of dollars. In what world can we
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): afford that? Well, it's a very complex topic. We don't have any functioning community hospitals left.
We have the
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): reserve currency, and
Man 15: we can keep writing debt until it causes an inflation crisis, which a lot of people thought would happen earlier and did not. And even our inflation crisis in the 2020s was mild by global
Man 6: standards. So accordingly, we've got plenty of room
Man 6: for the big enchilada, which is an Iran war.
Speaker 41: Yeah.
Speaker 80: So this, it just feels like a big deal. It's
a big
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): deal. To me,
and it
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): feels like it's worth, I mean, certainly if you comment on this, you do ask yourself, is it really worth it? You know, do I want to get into this? By the way, a lot of people I really like and I'm friends with violently disagree. So you run the risk,
which I
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): really don't want, of rupturing friendships over it. That's the last thing I want ever. Yeah.
And
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): you think, maybe I should be quiet, but it does seem like that's a huge step. And at the very least, the public ought to understand
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): that there are highly motivated people pushing us toward that. Do
you think
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): that we will participate in a military action
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): against Iran? Well, the big question is right now,
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): so there's a new Iranian president. So the previous Iranian president died along with his foreign minister in a helicopter accident over the summer.
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): - A little mysterious. - Are you gonna use air quotes around accident or?
- I
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): mean, a lot of things happened last year. It's very possible. I mean, I don't think-
Speaker 81: - Everyone got killed last year. - So many accidents. - The
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): Iranians equipment, helicopter equipment is to my understanding
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): is old. And it is a rough part of the world and it's possible that
it,
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): It's
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): likely that it just went down. And again, I would say...
I
Speaker 82 (lower-pitched voice): would not fly in a helicopter with Iranian officials. I'm just telling you that.
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): And again, if you think it was Israel, the Israelis
Man 15: pretty much took credit or didn't deny all the other assassinations that occurred last year. I don't, you know.
Speaker 83: The meeting of Hamas leadership, et cetera, et cetera, et cetera. Just for
Man 17: the record, I try to suspend judgment because...
Man 17: I know a lot about what countries do.
And I
Man 11: do think, there's one thing I'll say in support of Israel, I do think that it is,
you
Speaker 82 (lower-pitched voice): know, it isn't fair to just single out Israel and say they're doing naughty stuff. Like lots of people are doing naughty stuff.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): That's just a fact. My only, you know, the only point where I would feel like I want to say something
is if
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): the United States gets sucked into it. It's like that now, now we're talking about our interests, my country
is,
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): where my family's from. And I think it's fair to speak up then.
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): - Yeah, so I guess maybe the 2025 zoom out, you would say there was an election in Iran right afterwards. - Yes. -
A lot of people
Man 6: disagree with our perspective, will disagree with this term, but the more moderate candidate, people think there are no moderates within the regime, but the less hardcore candidate won. - Yes. - This
Man 23: is the first time this has happened since Trump left the Iran deal.
Man 23: and this person uh it is not clear how much power he has within the system the supreme
Man 15: leader is old it's not clear how old um and there will be a succession crisis to succeed the supreme leader should
Man 6: he die yeah so it is this weird situation where every time iran is in a crisis and their crisis right now they're in an electricity crisis by all reporting
Man 6: Again, don't know if we can trust all the reporting, but they can't keep the lights on in Tehran fully. And what will they do? And so every time Iran is at a decision point, there is a fracas between what
I will call
Man 15: the moderates and the hardliners within their government. The hardliners want to go for the bomb. They think we can't trust anybody. Right. We need to get...
The
Man 6: bomb, they also recently signed a mutual defense pact, just short of mutual defense pact,
but a
Man 6: security arrangement with the Russians. So they seem to have a bunker mentality right
Man 15: now. If US intelligence or Israeli intelligence or Western intelligence assesses that they are going for the
Man 6: bomb in a real way, so they can either be true or false, but if they assess it, then there will be severe,
Man 6: on the new administration
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): to do airstrikes on Iranian nuclear. - I get it, look, I don't want Iran to get the
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): bomb. I don't want anyone to get the bomb. I'm against the bomb, okay?
But I was around
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): when Pakistan got the bomb, and Pakistan is a country with a lot of wonderful people
Man 4: in it, kind of a great country in a lot of ways.
Spent a fair
Man 4: amount of time there. However, the government of Pakistan
is...
Man 4: It's arguably scarier than it is.
You
Speaker 44: think? Harbored Osama bin Laden,
Man 17: et cetera. ISI has been, you know, really a source of disorder in South Asia for a long time. And they've
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): exported nuclear technology, including to North Korea. So no one's
ever said
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): anything about that. Like, it's not a crisis that the Islamic Republic of Pakistan has the bomb. I don't really get it.
Speaker 85: I mean, why was that not a crisis? Why do we do nothing to stop that? I
Man 61: guess it occurred basically when the U.S. was still quasi pro-Pakistan over India. And it was— That was a bad bet, by the way. It
was a
Man 61: Nixonian bet, actually. He really didn't like Indira Gandhi. It
was
Speaker 13: basically— Okay, well, I think we can say longitudinally that was a bad bet. He just didn't like one person, and it didn't really matter. That was like betting on
Speaker 82 (lower-pitched voice): Wang computers over Apple. It just kind of didn't turn out.
Speaker 82 (lower-pitched voice): yeah
Speaker 87 (lower-pitched voice): so i
i'm not
Speaker 87 (lower-pitched voice): holding a wing in my so but but the
Speaker 88: point is might
want to
Speaker 88: cut that
Speaker 87 (lower-pitched voice): this is a
Speaker 88: bit of a so we're
Speaker 89: keeping the wang in okay yeah um look i think all i'm saying my father sold wing computers oh i'm so sorry i didn't mean to make it
Man 23: personal no no well then no it's just it's at one point the top sales in the country of wing computers yeah
Speaker 92: your father sold some wings
Man 23: yes are we is this actually going on of
Speaker 93: course it's actually All right, all right, yes, yes, yes, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 95: R.I.P. This is hard
Man 11: hitting. It was five years ago this month that people started to drop dead in the central Chinese city of Wuhan. Five years since the beginning of COVID. And yet, for some reason, we still don't know answers to the most basic questions. And one man knows those answers. His name is Dr. Tony Fauci. And now a documentary filmmaker called Jenner First is out with a new film explaining exactly what happened.
Speaker 96: The film is called Thank You, Dr. Fauci. We'll see it exclusively here on Twitter.
Speaker 96: on TCN. Look,
Speaker 55 (lower-pitched voice): all I'm saying is it's important to maybe dial back a little bit on the moral outrage and
Man 11: assess the world as it is, assess
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): what you can do, you know, create a hierarchy of priorities. Like, we don't want other countries to get nuclear weapons. I think that's, I'm with the neocons 100% on that. But, you know, in a complicated world that we don't actually control, what will, you know, what can we do? What are the limits of our power? Yeah.
Given
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): a lot of other factors like our domestics, our economy, the needs of our people,
Speaker 97: like you can't do everything.
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): That's all I'm saying. Yeah, no, I mean, so I think Trump should complete the work of his first term,
Man 15: which is he revoked the JCPOA, the Obama-Iran deal, and he should do a Trump-Iran deal.
Man 15: - Well, he's
Speaker 98: sending Wyckoff over to do that. -
Man 15: Yeah, so Wyckoff, the aforementioned, not only did what he did with the
Man 6: Israelis, he was promoted for it, per reporting. It has not been confirmed to my understanding by the transition or the White House. But per the FT, and I believe another outlet, Wyckoff is getting, quote, the Iran file. Within the Trump universe, that's as much power as the president
Man 15: wants to give it.
As of
Man 15: filming, his role is expanding. And if Trump wants a lasting legacy of peace and prosperity, there needs to be an accommodation with the de facto government of Iran. So if,
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): of course there
Speaker 99: does. This is just, this is totally insane. It's counter to our interests, I guess, is what I would say. If you were
Speaker 55 (lower-pitched voice): Trump...
And
Speaker 55 (lower-pitched voice): you say to Steve Whitcoff, hey, Steve Whitcoff, go get a ceasefire in place.
And he
Speaker 55 (lower-pitched voice): comes back like 20 minutes later with a ceasefire.
Speaker 100: Wouldn't you say, OK? We like that pace. I like
Speaker 40: that pace. Wouldn't you send him to Iran? I would.
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): Yes.
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): Yes. Yeah. I mean, I think I yeah, I mean, I mean, and this is actually something both Trump and Obama, who apparently
Man 15: get along now, at least perfunctorily. Yeah. Agreed on. Well, they both just like Michelle, I think. So they remember Obama on the debate stage in 08 said and he was he was just how down for this, whatever you think of Barack Obama, said we should meet with the Iranian leaders.
Man 15: face-to-face and trump did uh similar uh maneuvers yeah why wouldn't you with kim jong-un etc etc and again he's sucking up to dictators oh shut up i mean i mean was
Speaker 103: north korea policy more stable from 2017 to 2021 or 2021 to 2025 i don't think after
Man 4: 25 years of this nonsense killing dictators and watching their
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): countries become more chaotic and more dangerous to
the
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): That we have any obligation to listen to people who
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): chirp like that.
Man 23: No. Sucking up
Speaker 104: to TikTok. Shut up. To link it all. We
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): don't know
Man 23: anything, actually. So we started this conversation with, you know, sort of the campaign
Man 15: against the cadres that are now serving Secretary Hexeth.
The people that are
Man 15: leading it, as far as I can infer, are oftentimes many of the people that were behind the original Iraq War.
Man 15: And so, well, yeah, yeah. So this may seem obvious. I'm
Speaker 37: 55. So this is driving me completely insane. I thought after we discovered that the
Speaker 39 (lower-pitched voice): pretext of the war was a lie, that those people would, I don't know, don ashes, sackcloth and go like sit on a pillar for 10 years. I
Speaker 105: think a lot of Americans assume that they did. So we do this for a living. They went on the World Bank and
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): they still run the State Department. And Toria Nuland, who was an architect of the Iraq War, was an architect of the Ukraine War. Like this, it just doesn't end.
Man 15: But most
Man 15: Americans have real jobs and don't know this, and so these people are disguised or shrouded from public view, and they are still quite effective at driving home an agenda. In fact, I would assume
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): they will win absent pushback. Oh, they'll definitely win absent pushback. Oh, 100%. Yeah. So they are
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): still- That's why I want to interview you. Yeah, they're still hegemonic, even if they're a minority government, so to speak.
Yeah.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): And I, and I, I'm, cause I'm, I spent my life in the media. I'm very kind
of
Man 11: fixated on their enablers, their agents in the
Man 4: American news media. And one of them who's working has been working for years on their behalf, on behalf of permanent Washington, the foreign policy establishment, every bad idea is Jennifer Griffin at Fox, the Pentagon reporter,
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): who is now, you know, basically texting
the media.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): domino is that the michael domino yeah is you know running around on behalf of um you know her sources at the pentagon doing their bidding trying to torpedo these guys because the permanent staff doesn't want to be challenged on anything and okay you know there's a role for that kind
of
But
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): it's a little crazy that,
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): like, a supposed news reporter would be acting like that. I'm not guessing. This is a fact.
Speaker 74 (lower-pitched voice): She's doing that right now and has been doing that kind of thing for as long as I've been paying attention, like, a couple decades. How does that continue? Yeah, I
Speaker 107: don't know her personally, but what I
Man 61: will say is the role of most Pentagon reporters has always struck me since I've done this as extremely hierarchical.
Man 61: I
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): mean...
What do
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): you mean by hierarchical? It almost felt like the reporters worked for the Pentagon. Well,
Speaker 108: of course they... Yeah. So, I
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): mean, in any place that I've worked that had a Pentagon correspondent, and that was the only way you stayed in the room.
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): And...
Speaker 39 (lower-pitched voice): Isn't this a democracy where
we have civilian
Speaker 39 (lower-pitched voice): command of the armed forces and the
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): entire federal government works for the population of the country, its voters, its citizens, its constituents, shareholders,
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): no...
There's
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): no sense of that whatsoever in Washington at all. Yeah. It's like, what are you doing here? I
Speaker 109: think it's fast moving. I mean, you didn't see criticisms or skepticisms of
Man 6: the military from the right until the very last few years, including from the new president, including from organs of conservative media. I think it started with Mark Milley.
Man 6: but also the
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): sort of- Well, some of us were at it before that.
Speaker 110: Troy, I know, but in public opinion service- It was
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): considered a fringe position. It's not fringe.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah. You know, I just refer you back to the pivot point in American politics in my lifetime, which was the 2016
Man 4: debate in Greenville, South Carolina, where Donald Trump, home of the highest percentage of military veterans of any state, famously-
And
Man 4: Donald Trump came out
Speaker 20 (lower-pitched voice): against the Iraq War and all the dumbos at the channel I work for and in Washington are like, oh,
Speaker 44: he's lost it now. He'll never get the nomination. He's offended all the veterans. And, of course, all the guys whose lives were
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): destroyed fighting these wars, not on behalf of the United States, not to the benefit of the United
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): States. They were filled with many emotions, frustration, shame, rage, sadness, and they
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): immediately
died.
knew what
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): he was talking about, and no one in D.C. knew
what he was talking
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): about. I think he overperformed his polling. So,
Speaker 60 (lower-pitched voice): like, he
Man 15: was polling a certain—he was ahead, and the Bush family came in.
Man 6: That's when—it was the last stand for Mr. Jeb in February of 2016. And George W. Bush campaigned finally for Jeb, and it was like, we've got to keep him in the race, we're going to make our stand, and he did the big, fat mistake—
Man 6: That is a rock debate.
Man 15: And I think Trump is up 10 or 15. I think he won by over 20 in that debate.
Man 23: Don't quote me on that, but it was something like that. It was right before the primary. It was over the
Man 15: polling. So like not only did he not go down and still won, he went up and then clearly triumphed.
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): That was the moment when I was just, you know, whatever
Man 4: his flaws, I was for Trump because here was a guy telling a real truth, a hard truth that no one wanted him to tell and was...
And I
Man 4: just felt like that's consistent with my principles and beliefs, which is you ought to tell the truth, and a healthy country rewards people who tell the truth, not people
Speaker 112: who lie.
There's
Speaker 113 (lower-pitched voice): a cynical bet, though, I would say, and it's a cynical bet on
Trump,
Man 15: and it's a cynical bet on Americans, and it's a cynical bet on Republicans and independents.
Man 15: which is, I'll just, I'll just, let's use the actual language of center-left or left-wing media. It's a cult, and once the cult leader leaves, we can just go back to 2005 and implant the same old free trade, open borders. - Maybe. - Endless neoconservatism. And actually, the people
Man 6: that are driving
Man 6: the opposition to these selections and the Pentagon agree with President Trump's critics in spirit and
in
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): practice? You know, that's an interesting analysis. I mean, it's like MSNBC level dumb person analysis, but it's also like a real
Man 4: analysis. And there is a sense in which devotion to Trump has a religious quality to it. I mean, that's undeniable. I was just in DC for of the inauguration,
Speaker 114 (lower-pitched voice): I can confirm
that.
Speaker 114 (lower-pitched voice): Um, and there are a lot of reasons for that. I, you know,
Speaker 115: I, I think
a
Speaker 114 (lower-pitched voice): lot of voters feel like Trump is the only person who cares about them. He's their only option. And so they're on board regardless because where else are they going? And I think,
I think
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): that's true. A and B, I think that's a reflection of like how badly the leadership of the country has failed. Um,
people will take
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): anything other than that. But I also think saying true things out loud changes history.
I think
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): that's the lesson of history. The only people who actually changed history are not the ones who marshal the biggest armies, but the ones who speak the truth out loud. I think it's a holy act. I think
Speaker 114 (lower-pitched voice): it's a transformative act. And
all of
Speaker 114 (lower-pitched voice): history is the story of that act, actually. And sometimes it, you know, it takes centuries for the consequences to unfold, but they do. It's inevitable. It changes everything. That's why there's such
a...
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): a almost a crazed attempt to shut down people from speaking
Speaker 57: why speaking they don't care about violence they care about talking because they understand correctly that that's what matters over time right so once trump has said all this
stuff there's
Speaker 116: kind of no going back no do you think i mean that's my view i don't know no
Man 61: i don't i don't agree with the cynical bet i think it's a bad bet yes which is why the tactics are increasingly hysterical and marginal
Speaker 57: But we're robbed of like a real debate. I mean, I don't know. You know, if you think it's so important
to
Speaker 34 (lower-pitched voice): kill the leaders of Iran and get into a full-scale
war with a
Speaker 34 (lower-pitched voice): real country, which Iran is, which is part of a real coalition.
They
Speaker 118: won't say full-scale. They'll
Speaker 119: say that the Ayatollah has to go. It's very important to use
Speaker 60 (lower-pitched voice): as scary words as possible. Ayatollah, the Mullahs, the Islamic Republic emphasize, you know, and
Man 15: again,
Man 15: like uh basically the bin laden who's dead runs a country even though these different ethnicity and a different religion and so it doesn't really matter you're stupid and uh we need to do this again and like i i they won't say an invasion but again some of the people pushing uh this stuff didn't
Speaker 60 (lower-pitched voice): say an invasion in 1996.
Speaker 60 (lower-pitched voice): they softened the ground for it.
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): - But where's the debate on it? I guess that's the point. -
Speaker 120: There wasn't a debate.
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): - I mean, it's a
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): little harder here too, because on the question of Russia, it's been surprisingly effective for them to just
Man 11: dismiss all criticism as sponsored by Putin. Like you don't think it's a good
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): idea to prop up- - Speed is very important here. - The Zelensky government. You're a Putin puppet or whatever.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): - You want someone
Speaker 121: to do so many--
Speaker 122: - Can you really call like a white American Christian guy a puppet of the mullahs? Probably not. It's like, I don't think that works, right?
Does it? I guess they're
Speaker 123: trying it with Steve Wyckoff. You're a tool of cutter.
- Oh, so
Speaker 124: you're referring to, so-- - The Shiites. I
Speaker 93: just don't think as a rhetorical matter, it's quite as easy-- -
Man 15: Should we address the actual allegations? - Yes. - So Wyckoff, I believe, took his real estate firm, took some
Man 6: sort of investment from Qatar.
Man 6: And so first of all, I would say throughout the Trump entourage, a lot of them have worked with Gulf
Man 15: states. And as far as I can tell, the real estate business is rife with investments from Gulf states. And then additionally, as far as I'm aware, this
is
Speaker 125 (lower-pitched voice): hardly that man's net worth. Well, the domestic, I mean, you can't buy an apartment in New York because there's so much Chinese money in the residential
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): real estate market.
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): Okay, so the argument is what? You're only allowed to invest in your own country's real estate? Okay, let's start here.
Speaker 57: Let's ban foreign investment in our real estate markets. Oh, no, that's anti-capitalist. Just the whole thing doesn't make sense. What
are they
Speaker 88: saying? What?
-
Man 15: Well, with the Qatar argument specifically, I mean, I think it's an unusual place. It was supposed to be the eighth emirate. So it is separate from the UAE. It is the most conservative of those emirates, I would say, at least in terms of the government. They have a perspective. They spend money on media. They spend money on press junkets.
Man 15: uh they have an influence operation no question um but the idea that this small jetting uh you know uh lng dependent uh you
know uh
Man 15: peninsula uh controls u.s foreign policy hook line and sinker top to bottom um if
you
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): think that
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): I don't think you're extremely curious.
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): I mean, I do think it's worth having an honest, I've never seen one, there never has been one, but an honest conversation about foreign influence
Man 4: on American policy. I think that's a totally legitimate topic. And, you know, we've kind of done a lot of lying and pretending, for example, that Russia has like undue
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): influence over American foreign policy. It's absurd.
But why not have that
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): conversation? So are there foreign countries that exert influence on American policy?
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah,
for sure.
Whose
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): interests
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): supersede those of American citizens when, you know, in the minds of policymakers. And,
you know, there
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): may be some of those.
How would
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): we rank
Speaker 39 (lower-pitched voice): Qatar, you know,
in terms of
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): its
Speaker 39 (lower-pitched voice): influence?
Maybe
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): not
Speaker 39 (lower-pitched voice): in the top three.
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah, no. Right. So, just having lived in D.C., this whole conversation is
like so
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): infuriatingly false and just silly.
Speaker 126: Mm-hmm.
I
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): mean, are they running intel operations against us? There's a lot of Qatar surveillance in Washington, a lot of Qatar agents running around the Willard Hotel. I don't think so. Maybe, tell me. - Very well-disguised.
- Like, what are
Speaker 123: you talking about? I mean, our country's doing that. Are they hacking the Pentagon's mainframes? I don't think, oh, China's doing that.
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): - Yeah. - Right, okay, so. - Yeah, but making the allegation, though, is a kind of armor, though.
It
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): makes you seem informed. It makes you seem like
a
Speaker 60 (lower-pitched voice): sort of a spymaster You know, like I know something you don't and I'm I'm more serious Yeah, yeah, like like like let's not have a conversation and it's very anti-democratic small D It is it
Man 15: is it is not a green disagree
It is
Man 15: not saying we have different values and you know shaking each other hand and walking out of the room it is
It
Man 15: is
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): shutting down the spirit of the system. Well, so that's exactly the complaint that I have.
And that's
Man 4: the problem that I have with Barry Weiss. It's the problem I have with Jen Griffin. It's the problem I have with the Washington Post. And just so much of the
Man 11: media coverage of foreign policy is based on insinuation and like the cruelest sort of character-destroying
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): insinuations that you're not loyal to your own country. Yeah.
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): Um, and I'm sure they reach for the biggest,
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): they go, man, they go right for the face. And I just think that that's beneath a great nation like
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): ours. I think it's beneath any decent person to behave. If you have evidence that someone's
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): selling out his country, tell me what it is. But to start with that, to accuse Steve Wyckoff of being a tool of cutter, um,
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): it's like so over the top. I just feel like it's important to call out the people doing it and say, you're disgusting. We're not listening to you anymore. You
Speaker 127: have no influence except that that you project through aggression and threats. And
Speaker 128: like,
we're not
Speaker 128: playing along. I think a lot
Man 15: of it is effective in Republican politics. Yes. Because, you know, so you were there
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): for the inauguration, I observed a week ago. And, you know, I've always observed that...
is
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): usually when I meet someone
Man 61: from a red state, like a deep red state, Oklahoma or Alabama, it's often their first time in Washington, D.C. Yes. It's very
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): like a Roman province visiting Rome for the first time. Totally. I'm here from Gaul. Yeah. Show
me
Man 15: around. Yeah. Versus, I would say, Blue State America
Man 6: actually has a lot more, the coasts have a lot more familiarity with D.C. Yes. Back and forth, airport access, etc., etc. So when they hear...
Man 6: the argument going on in the Capitol, there's
Man 15: actually a de facto trust there that might be not as much there on the Democratic side. There's actually a more jaundiced cynicism on the Democratic side, so it's less effective. They assume that the, despite it all, despite all of the failures that you've announced, that you've reported on fairly tirelessly, they
Man 6: assume that the people in DC know what they're doing. And I'm not sure that's the greatest default assumption.
Speaker 115: Well, I mean, I think the track record is pretty, speaks conclusively. I mean,
Speaker 60 (lower-pitched voice): look, respectfully to the new president, I mean, Donald Trump, again, is the only U.S. president who was not a general or a former statewide official or federal official to get the presidency. And with all due respect to the new president.
Speaker 60 (lower-pitched voice): healthy country doesn't elect something like that. It had that level of outsider. That level of outsider could only exist within a polity that was deeply sick. And I think he knows
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): that. I think he recognizes that. And the fact that the Capitol
Speaker 60 (lower-pitched voice): doesn't imbibe that lesson, I think they're
Man 15: I mean, it's still bizarre 10 years on. I mean, Trump, June 2015, so it'll be June this year, 10 years of Trump, longer than Obama at this point, the Trump era, in spirit, in length. It's like, well, maybe there's
Man 23: something wrong with this country, but it's like a 5% recognition. It's not a 95% recognition.
Man 4: - I think national, I mean, first of all, I agree completely.
And I
Man 4: wrote a piece at the very beginning of this whole saga almost 10 years ago. - Donald
Speaker 130: Trump is shocking, vulgar, and right. - Yeah, he's winning 'cause you failed.
Speaker 130: It's simple, you
know,
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): obvious. Anyway, I don't think D.C. gets it, but I also think at this point, Trump is the most powerful president, certainly since
Man 4: Roosevelt. Interesting. And the potential for, you know, achieving his promises is really high. America has greater problems in its head since the Great Depression, maybe even bigger than it had then. And we have a chance to address
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): them. Probably not solve all of them, but make some headway on things that could help Americans. is sealing the border.
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): stopping the chaos, just taking a breather so we can figure out how to fix the country. And the only thing that could derail that is another foreign war. - We can't do it with this stuff.
Speaker 60 (lower-pitched voice): It is an actual choice. -
Man 4: It's an actual choice. - We cannot do the border if we do the Middle East. - So you had, what, 200,000 people a year dying of drug ODs and no one said anything
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): about it? And endless lectures about Ukraine? And it's no disrespect to the Ukrainians, who I really feel sorry for,
But
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): like, that's so unbelievable that that happened. It's like a bad dream. And now we've woken up from the dream and we have this chance.
And I'm
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): sorry, I just, you know, with respect to Barry Weiss and Jen Griffin, you can't do that to us again. I'm just not gonna go without a fight this time. We have to reorient toward our own interests. That's no disrespect to any other country, to our allies who we wish well and will help to the extent we can, but like the idea that we're responsible for all these other countries when we're dying here,
no mas
Speaker 100: is is that is that a radical position that's my actual position in my heart that's my actual position i i agree
Man 15: but it's it's it's very upsetting not only to uh leaders of some foreign countries um and this is not just the middle east we didn't even talk about russia ukraine but like i mean uh that perspective is obviously very very relevant for extricating the united states out of the russia ukraine war and almost every european
Man 15: the capital is unhappy with that. And you can have a conversation with a nice Danish person and you might agree on immigration or trade or wine. But you mentioned like, hey, I'm not really sure the United States should
be
Man 6: underwriting quagmire in Ukraine and like the conversation shuts down. It is stunning.
-
Man 4: Well, they're hell bent on suicide. The Western Europeans and not the Eastern Europeans or Central Europeans, but the Western Europeans have decided to kill
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): themselves.
And
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): it's almost like if someone's standing on a bridge or in a window of a skyscraper and you're trying to talk them back in, it's hard. And who knows why that happens? I think there's a supernatural element at work. It's my personal view, but whatever you think the cause is, that's what it is.
You destroy,
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): you blow up Nord Stream, destroy the German economy, and you're not allowed to say anything about it in Germany. I
don't know that
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): we can help you at that point. You know what I mean? Like if you're that intent on self-harm,
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): that anxious to destroy your own civilization, make it impossible for your children to live there,
then you're
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): killing yourself. You can't help someone who doesn't
want to
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): help himself. Like, go ahead and jump then.
Kind
Speaker 114 (lower-pitched voice): of, that's how I feel.
But just from an
Speaker 114 (lower-pitched voice): American perspective, like, all of this has been bad for us. There's no way to pretend otherwise, except to launch into some airy moral lecture about dictatorships and Winston Churchill and Neville Chamberlain or something.
Just
Speaker 118: shut up,
Speaker 114 (lower-pitched voice): okay?
the
Speaker 118: churchill thing is really it's just played
Speaker 114 (lower-pitched voice): out it's played out
Speaker 60 (lower-pitched voice): i mean it's played out in but there's a there's a there's a gamble that some of this stuff isn't played out though
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): i mean there's a there's a gamble that um that this i mean i think people
Man 15: have have this
Speaker 131: country has a generational
Man 15: problem right generations don't get along um i think that's fair for good reason yeah
Man 15: And I think there's just a bet that a lot of the voters that made the decisions in the 90s and 2000s are dumb and don't care about their kids' future and will vote for the exact same thing. Clearly they don't. Yeah. Sorry. And will exert pressure on the new administration to do the same thing.
Man 15: I think there's a bet that the president is a desperate, cynical man who will do whatever it takes when he's pressured. And I think
Speaker 60 (lower-pitched voice): the early evidence is that it's untrue. I mean, I don't I mean, the evidence is that Trump is less
Speaker 127: cynical than even his supporters thought he was. I think that's the truth. I
Speaker 113 (lower-pitched voice): mean, there's there's do you want to discuss the Pompeo, Brian Hook stuff?
Speaker 133: Yeah.
Speaker 133: I would. I was just reading the Barry Weiss editorial about how pulling Pompeo's... What did she say? I didn't read it. It's
Speaker 134: outrageous. It's a betrayal of Trump's promises. Is that what the free
Speaker 83: press argued?
Speaker 32: Yeah, that you
Man 17: can't, you're not allowed, you are
Man 11: required to pay for Mike Pompeo's security detail.
And I
Man 11: will just say point blank as someone who has faced greater physical
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): threats than Mike Pompeo, I can promise you that.
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): I, you know, if I have security, I pay for it myself. Like, wow, why does Mike Pompeo as a private citizen get to stick me with the bill for his security detail? Like, how does that work, Barry Weiss? And the point is that Mike Pompeo is a faithful servant of the kind of ideas
Man 4: that,
Man 4: she is here to push on the rest of us and therefore he will be defended at all costs. But, but like, let's just be honest about what's going on. Anyway, sorry.
Man 15: Yeah. I mean, details roll off. The government doesn't usually
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): advertise it. Everyone's got a detail. Fauci has a detail. Yeah. Yeah. Because he's in my dog park in Washington and I hear about it. I think the interesting
Man 6: thing, so it's very easy to just glaze over Trump fighting with officials and,
Man 6: blah blah blah blah blah you know and sort of the the example of this is trump versus bolton and we talk about that and it's fun but it's kind of over right bolton's not in the mix and uh
Speaker 125 (lower-pitched voice): release of trump and like um but he's still got bits of egg in his mustache and i don't have his cell anymore so i can't tell him but
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): he needs
Man 15: to fix that yeah
i so um
Man 15: pompeo and hook
I
Man 15: mean, look. Tell us who they are. Mike Pompeo. Yeah, so Mike Pompeo was the former Secretary of State, former CIA director, former Kansas congressman, former West Point valedictorian. Harvard graduate. Harvard law graduate.
Speaker 136: Osimic user.
Speaker 136: Sorry, I'm doing
Speaker 137: the whole CV here.
Speaker 125 (lower-pitched voice): Okay, right. So, and he was... I'm so bitchy. I'm so sorry that I said that. It's beneath me. I shouldn't have said that. The
Speaker 71: Bolton-Trump feud is old. The disagreement
Man 15: with Pompeo is potentially quite new. And so, by all available information, Pompeo was in the mix for Secretary of Defense, most likely, in the days after the...
Man 15: So much so that his son, Donald Trump Jr., intervened in a sort of online campaign and, you know, other allies within that milieu stopped both Pompeo and the former U.N. ambassador, South Carolinian governor, Nikki Haley, from getting administration posts. I had
Speaker 139: heard about that. Yeah,
Man 17: yeah. Pompeo. Patriotic Americans rallied as they did in Boston in the 18th century.
To act
Man 17: on behalf of their nation at some personal
Speaker 125 (lower-pitched voice): risk, but they did it anyway. Unsung heroes. One of Pompeo's
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): former deputies, Brian Hook, who ran something called the Iran Study Group and had various other portfolios and titles at the State Department. He's actually someone Pompeo inherited from Rex Tillerson, his predecessor. He kept him on.
Man 6: Brian Hook at...
Man 6: various points throughout the transition in the last 100 days was reported to be running the state department's transition
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): at some point then was rumored again rumors i don't it's rumored i don't i don't post about it i don't tweet it out i don't write about it but it was rumored to have been fired very unclear uh trump uh in the days leading up to him taking the oval office uh oath Issues
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): essentially an
enormous
Speaker 140 (lower-pitched voice): denunciation, a fought-flaw against Mr. Hook. Extraordinary to say, not only like, is this guy not in the mix, I hate him. And he said that, so that
Man 15: occurred. And then additionally, both Hook and Pompeo's security detail
Man 61: was removed in the last few days.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): - I don't know
Speaker 133: that Brian Hook has served in government in four years. - He definitely has not served Mr. Biden. - Why
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): would he have a security detail
paid
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): for by taxpayers? - Not an expert on who gets secret service details. - But can I just, I
just want to
Man 23: say. - I can actually directly answer that. - Yeah. - So the key thing here is that there is an allegation, a belief, many in the intelligence community believes this,
Man 23: that
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): there were serious, credible plans by the Iranians to assassinate members of the Trump high command, as it
Man 15: were. So Trump, Hook, John Bolton, et cetera, et cetera, in revenge principally for the Soleimani assassination. - 'Cause they've been
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): committing a lot of terror attacks in the United States, you've noticed. Oh no, no, that was in Tifa.
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): And so that is the essential, that is the causes. I'm just going to have to scoff at all of it. I've heard
Speaker 60 (lower-pitched voice): a lot of this. I hear this all the time. I think the key thing here is the critique on Trump always was he fired Bolton, but he didn't really understand why. So he
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): just, he soured on the guy, but he didn't change any like policy. You know, he didn't learn. This is the sort of pedantic way of
Man 15: looking at the president. But with the Hook and Pompeo
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): and removal from his inner circle. There is, I think, very credible evidence that Trump's personal grudges
Man 6: are now blending quite heavily with policy. He doesn't trust the Iran hawk old guard. A lot of the Iran hawk old guard think tanks struck out.
in
Man 6: getting
Man 15: transition officials and officials in this government. And again, circled around this very unlikely Pentagon, helmed by a guy who has changed his life, it appears, in pretty severe ways over the last five years, both ideologically and morally, is this very new Pentagon that is now being targeted by all the usual suspects
Speaker 87 (lower-pitched voice): And it is the biggest story in American politics that people aren't talking about.
Speaker 142: So if I could sum up what I think you're saying, it is that Donald Trump may have actually broken
Speaker 20 (lower-pitched voice): the grip of the neocons on Washington. I
mean, you
Speaker 87 (lower-pitched voice): control the Pentagon. You control the military. I mean, it's the—
It
Speaker 143: just seems like this is—because there was always this question about Trump. Like, you get up and you give these speeches—
Speaker 143: Where you say, we don't want more
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): pointless wars, I believe in peace, through strength. He's not a wuss, he's not Jimmy Carter, but like, you know, you assert American power, but you don't embroil a country in wars that you can't win for
no
Speaker 47: reason.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): It's a very moderate, sensible,
Man 4: common sense, I would say, view. So you say those things, but then you hire John
Bolton.
the
Man 4: question is why and trump would say i've heard him say well i heard bolt i beg your pardon i heard bolton because he's a lunatic and he's a warmonger freak he's obviously like watching war porn late at night and
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): people can smell that on him and so when he goes into a negotiation he scares the crap out of everybody and then i
show up you know
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): he's the heavy and he's the backup i mean i've
And I
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): didn't know if I believe that or not, but I'm starting
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): to think
that
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): I
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): should have just believed him because it sounds like Trump's actual
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): instincts are what he says they are.
Speaker 60 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah. I mean, the Bolton firing itself is, again, ancient history, but it's circled around
Man 15: an issue of policy. Oh, I remember. Yeah. So, I mean, Trump had invited the Taliban,
Man 6: which was then the outlaw party.
not
Man 6: government of Afghanistan, as it is today, to Camp David on
Speaker 88: 9-11. I just love the sound of it. So Trump invited the Taliban to Camp David. He did. He literally did that. I mean, I'm just reporting the facts here. It's a great sentence.
Speaker 100: So Donald Trump invited the Taliban. So tonight, who's coming for dinner tonight at Camp David? Oh, the Taliban will be here.
Man 26: Bolton was wiped out before this meeting never happened, but it was the instigating...
Man 26: incident for the final breakdown of their relationship.
Speaker 82 (lower-pitched voice): I do think it's important Kurt to just recognize
Man 11: the inherent hilarity of a lot of you know it is in addition to being grave and you know historically significant it's very funny.
Speaker 144: Very funny a lot of this stuff is very funny. It's
sort of
Speaker 144: funny yeah yeah it's pretty great. Yeah
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): so under you're very restrained and business
Man 17: like and precise as a reporter should be as an editor should be but the story that you're telling I think I don't want to put words in your mouth is a
is a
Man 17: story of, like, real change, finally, we actually appear to be getting to, like, a foreign policy that puts America close to
Speaker 145: the center
of the
Speaker 145: action. Yeah.
Is that what
Speaker 146: you're seeing? No. I mean, if he sees this
Man 61: through, this is the biggest presidency. Certainly, since Reagan, you alluded to FDR. I
Man 6: mean, it is moving the ship of state. And...
Man 6: People are going to try to stop him from doing it. Yes.
Speaker 60 (lower-pitched voice): But they're not going to say that he's bad, though. They're going to go after... No one will ever say, right. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Well, I just
Speaker 142: want to countersign
Man 17: them by saying, I think what you're saying is true. I think it's real.
And I've never
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): admired Trump more. I
don't think I'm
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): going to ask this around the Trump question, but this is like, America really needs this. It's just super important.
And
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): it's not radical at all. It's not attacking anyone or canceling our allyship with any country at all. It's just readjusting expectations for
what we
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): can achieve. The reason
Man 6: that I started covering war on foreign policy principally is that the reality is that U.S. domestic policy is a morass. It's impossible to get anything done. Obama tried to do a health care plan. Six years in, they couldn't even have the website working. You know, the country is hard to govern. but extra
Man 6: Externally, the
Speaker 88: president is imperial. He's God. Quite literally the most
Man 15: powerful person on earth. And if you want to burnish a legacy real quick, you do big things in foreign policy. You do shocking things in foreign policy. That's what all the Republican senators have figured out. You do surprising things in foreign policy.
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): You're John McCain. Like you're, you know, whatever. You've got a lot of problems.
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): in your personal and public life, but you can bomb around Eastern Europe and get treated like an emperor. Right. And feel like you're doing something. You're, you know, Jim Risch or Mike Rounds or some like U.S. senator nobody's ever heard of, even in his home state. But when you travel to Romania to tour a NATO base, people are like,
Speaker 148: oh, you know, Senator Risch is here. You know, it's like.
It's a
Speaker 100: foreign relations chair. Yeah. So. Right. Yeah. Yeah. And
like,
So
Speaker 100: that's a, that's a big, that's a big motivator for our lawmakers, isn't it? Sure. For sure.
Speaker 58: I mean, yeah. I mean. You go to Idaho Falls and no one's like, oh, I can't believe you're here. But you know. Chairman Risch. Chairman, Chairman Risch. It's like such an absurd. It's anyway, excuse me. Interesting.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): So,
and I
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): interrupted you because I can't, I can't control myself. Zero self-control.
get on
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): the topic of pizza or neocons and I'm just out of control. Tell
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): me your analysis of Trump canceling the security details for Brian Hook and Mike Pompeo.
Speaker 149: Well,
he
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): seems to have the authentic view that these people can afford it, especially with Fauci and especially with Bolton.
Man 15: He specifically flagged them. Yeah. And Pompeo,
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): who's
now
Man 61: running around being like, I'm actually a businessman.
He's
Man 61: on a board of a Ukrainian
Speaker 125 (lower-pitched voice): company as well. - Well, he's
Speaker 151: on, I think, more than one board, but he's certainly running around, including with people I know, saying, "I'm really kind of a business guy."
Man 23: - Look, I mean, so the Pompeo thing is supremely interesting because I think it's
Man 15: somebody who probably would have positioned himself to run in a major way had Trump lost. I think it's somebody who's not gonna quit being president. This is not an unintelligent man.
Man 15: Uh,
Speaker 152: this is, yeah, this is,
Man 15: he's not dumb. This is a real fighter. Um, and, uh, I don't want to say he's part of the cynical bet crowd, but he's making a bet that the Trump thing will pass and I will be able to steamroll people like Vance and even Rubio in the future because I'm more vicious. And, um, in the meantime, uh, you know, maybe make some money, uh,
Man 15: influence the debate, et cetera, et cetera. And he's very impressive if you don't know. I mean, if you don't come in with huge foreign policy convictions as I think
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): you and I do, he can be very persuasive. - Just for the record, I had no
Speaker 153: foreign policy convictions. I don't think I'm ideological on the question at all. I just think in general, our foreign policy should serve the nation.
-
Speaker 7: I am. I mean, so I think that's what's very interesting
about
Speaker 7: some of these Pentagon picks, not to keep linking it
Man 15: back, but also the vice president. A lot of these people, my generation, the millennials, fought in these wars. Oh, yeah. And although the baby boomers, forget
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): it, we're now old, you know, and we grew up and we're quite mad about it. And it's a
Speaker 154: bipartisan thing.
Man 15: It's not just like a Democrat, you know, anti-Iraq war, indie music thing. It's like young Republican people hate it too. And they
Speaker 155: might hate it
more.
Man 23: actually which is actually the interesting thing the and the Republican Party frankly might under Trump might be a vessel of anti-war
Man 6: sentiment far more effectively than the Democrats I mean I didn't see a lot of protests for the Ukraine war the Israel stuff was pretty interesting and that was probably was
Man 15: number one threat to Biden circa April remember for sure
but
Man 15: you know if you look at the conversation online if you look at the sentiments of of younger conservatives young republicans the anti-war stuff is big and it's not going anywhere and i think that also drives a sense of a timetable which is um you know we've got these older people in their 60s 70s 80s and 90s they have a certain belief set they're the people that voted for the stuff in the 90s and 2000s and we get this get this stuff done now before the united states turns um you know on both parties on this stuff
And
Speaker 32: this was always, this was... So we can't afford it anymore and our allies pivot to China and sell even more defense technology
Man 17: to China. Yeah. I
do think
Man 17: they're, okay, so the backbone of support for these wars has been evangelicals. Let's just be blunt about it.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): It's everyone, you know, beats up on the neocons or whatever, these fervid intellectuals in Washington. But really the foot soldiers of this have been Fox News viewers who are not...
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): ideological they're not intellectuals they're not they're just normal american patriotic heavily evangelical people
and the
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): truth is i think a lot of them are beginning to recognize that their religion does not support this at all yeah it's really clear genesis 6 why do we have the flood why does god kill everything on earth
all the
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): people except no one in his family all the animals except the ones in the ark why does he do that
Speaker 74 (lower-pitched voice): he spells it right out because they're committing violence. That's
why.
So
Speaker 117: it's like the idea that, I mean,
the
Speaker 57: Iraq war breaks out and all these preachers are like, no, no, no, really, we have to fight Islam and kill all these people and that's what God wants. That's not what it says at all. And
there's no
Speaker 57: mention of any specific
secular
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): government in the New Testament. Sorry, guys. And I
think a
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): lot of Christians are beginning to realize this. It doesn't, because you're a Christian doesn't mean you have a specific political agenda at all, I don't think. Yeah.
But
Speaker 37: if your political agenda is like violence, that's prohibited. Sorry. And I just, it could not be clear. It's on every freaking page.
So I
Speaker 37: don't know the
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): deception involved in this was just like mind boggling that these preachers could get up on Fox News and tell you that like, yeah, killing people is what Jesus wants. No, that's not true.
And I just
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): feel among people I
Speaker 42: know.
a
Speaker 42: growing recognition of that. And I think it's a huge problem for the war lobby, which has used these people as its supporters. And you see it in the Congress. You know, I'm an evangelical and I'm for another war with somebody.
No, you can't do
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): that anymore. I'm hoping people are zoned out. You do think that? Yeah, I think they're hoping the country's old,
Man 6: tired, zoned out, can't oppose it. And they're hoping that these initiatives can be achieved piecemeal.
Man 6: You know, start by bombing Iran here,
et
Man 61: cetera, et cetera. Maybe the government will collapse, et cetera, et cetera, et cetera. To be
replaced by what? The
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): same people who replaced Assad and Gaddafi and Saddam and the Taliban. I mean, I think, okay, I
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): mean, to take the other side, I mean, I mean, the Assad thing is that's like pretty close to the best case scenario of
Man 61: how that could have gone. I think in Iran, it would go way, way, way worse. It's a much bigger
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): country.
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): it's hard to know you're rolling the dice you know you start killing people and things go sideways like you
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): think it's it's pretty close to iraq and afghanistan combined right
Man 15: you have it feels that way to me you have urban you have you have the you have the capacity for major urban violence a la
Man 6: iraq you have huge cities not that kabul is small but you know you have that and then additionally
Man 15: you have the mountain
element so
Man 15: any any outlaw
Man 15: contingent can just flee there i mean and and we learned this with our southern neighbor right why is mexico ungovernable the mountains
Man 61: you just just just flee i mean the entire coastline right why is kentucky ungovernable same reason okay yeah yeah yeah i mean so just kidding no no i mean it's i mean it's it's hard to it would be very very very difficult and ask saddam hussein who tried to invade iran and uh didn't work
Man 15: out for mr hussein a lot of things didn't so
Speaker 55 (lower-pitched voice): No, I agree completely. Well, you have actually given me... I
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): asked you to come for this conversation. It's late at night. I was very exercised about it. You were nice enough to come. And we're in a hotel room in some city,
but I
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): thought I was going to be more depressed by the end, but actually I feel really heartened by what you said.
Thank you for
Speaker 76: having me.
Well, thank
Speaker 76: you for making me feel a lot better. Kurt Mills. Appreciate it. Thank you.
So it turns out
Speaker 157: that YouTube is suppressing this show. On one level, that's not surprising, that's what they do. But on another level,
Speaker 158: it's shocking. With everything that's going on in the world right now, all the change taking place in our economy and our
Speaker 39 (lower-pitched voice): politics, with the wars on the cusp of fighting right now, Google has decided you should have less information rather than more. And that is totally wrong. It's immoral. What can you do about it?
Speaker 39 (lower-pitched voice): Well, we could whine about it. That's a waste of time. We're not in charge of Google. Or we could find a way around it, a way that you could actually get information that is true, not intentionally deceptive. The way to do that on YouTube, we think, is to subscribe to our channel. Subscribe. Hit the little bell icon to be notified when we upload and share this video. That way, you'll have a much higher chance of hearing actual news and information. So we hope that you'll do that.